One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
Reverse Mountain
‫الجبل المعكوس‬
What's wrong, Zoro?
‫ما خطبك يا زورو؟‬
You've had a serious look on your face for a while.
‫يعلو وجهك تعبيرٌ جادٌ منذ فترة‬
Well, I might just be imagining things, but...
‫حسنٌ... آمل أنّ هذا من وحي خيالي، ولكن...‬
But what?
‫لكن ماذا؟‬
I feel like the ship hasn't moved in a while.
‫أشعر أنّ السفينة لم تتحرك منذ مدة‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
Now that you mention it, the sail isn't catching any wind...
‫على ذِكر ذلك، لم تهبّ أيّ رياح على الشراع‬
Oh no...!
‫تبًّا!‬
We've entered the Calm Belt!
‫دخلنا الحزام الهادئ!‬
The Balm Belt?
‫الحزام الهاذي؟‬
The heck is that?
‫ما هذا؟‬
The Calm Belt! A sea where nothing moves a muscle!
‫الحزام الهادئ! إنه بحرٌ يغمره السُّكون‬
You grew some muscle?
‫تلاعب لفظي من لوفي‬
No, you idiot!
‫أحمق!‬
Was that an earthquake?
‫ما الخطب؟ أهذا زلزال؟‬
An earthquake? But we're at sea.
‫زلزال؟ ولكننا على البحر‬
Come on, guys, focus!
‫كفاكُم حديثًا!‬
Hoist the sails and start paddling!
‫اربطوا الأشرعة وابدؤوا التجديف!‬
Put the ship back on course, now!
‫أعيدونا إلى مسارنا السابق!‬
As you wish, Nami!
‫حاضر يا نامي-سان!‬
What are you panicking about?
‫لماذا أنتِ مذعورة؟‬
And why paddle? This is a sailboat.
‫هذه سفينة شراعية، كيف سنجدف بها؟‬
Yeah, why?
‫صحيح‬
Just shut up and do as I say! We're in big trouble!
‫افعلوا ما أقوله فحسب! إنّنا في ورطة‬
But the sea is nice and quiet here.
‫ولكن البحرَ هادئ‬
Yeah.
‫أجل‬
Alright, fine! I'll explain!
‫يا إلهي! طيب، سأشرح لكم‬
Listen. Since we were in such a hurry, we went farther south than intended!
‫اسمعوا، بما أننا هربنا على عجل فقد اتجهنا جنوبًا أكثر مما خططنا‬
So we're in the Grand Line now?
‫أنحنٌ في الغراند لاين إذًا؟‬
Alright!
‫وأخيرًا!‬
If it was that easy, anyone could enter!
‫لو كان دخوله بهذه البساطة، لدخله أيّ أحد‬
Look here.
‫انظروا‬
The Grand Line runs between these two strips of sea.
‫تقع وجهتنا الغراند لاين بين منطقتين بحريّتين‬
Are you following? The two strips are called the Calm Belts.
‫أفهمتم؟ ما يُحيط به من الجانبين يُعرَف بالحزام الهادئ‬
The reason's unknown, but no wind or currents flow through them.
‫إنّه يخلو من الرياح والتيارات، ولا يُعرَف السبب‬
These seas are completely calm.
‫إنها منطقة بحرية ساكنة تمامًا‬
Sailboats need wind to move so it's very dangerous—
‫السفن الشراعية لا تتحرك من دون رياح، لذا فالوضع خطير‬
maybe even fatal—without it!
‫وكأنها منطقة مميتة لها‬
Did you get all that, Luffy?
‫أفهمتَ يا لوفي؟‬
Yeah. Basically, we're in trouble.
‫أجل. فهمتُ أنّنا في ورطة‬
That explains the lack of wind.
‫هذا يُفسّر انعدام الرياح‬
Not much we can do if the ship can't move.
‫لا حيلة لنا إن لم تتحرّك السفينة‬
Can't we just wait for wind to–
‫علينا انتظار هبوب الرياح‬
I just explained this! Wind won't blow no matter how long you wait here!
‫ألم أشرح ذلك توًّا؟ لن تهبّ الرياح مهما انتظرنا‬
And that's not all!
‫وليس هذا فحسب‬
There's another reason this area is dangerous!
‫ثمّة سبب آخر يجعل هذه المنطقة خطيرة‬
The Calm Belt is–
‫إن الحزام الهادئ...‬
What's going on?
‫ما الذي يحدث؟!‬
They're here!
‫ها هم!‬
What's that?
‫ما هذا؟‬
Th-Th-They're...
‫إ-إ-إنهم...‬
They're huge!
‫ضِخام!‬
The Calm Belt is a nest of sea kings.
‫إن الحزام الهادئ وكر ملوك البحر،‬
Specifically colossal ones.
‫وخاصةً الضخام منهم‬
They're the other reason people can't cross the Calm Belt...
‫وجودهم هو السبب الآخر لتجنّب الناس الحزام الهادئ‬
What do we do now?
‫ماذا سنفعل الآن؟‬
F-For the time being, no one move.
‫فـ-في الوقت الراهن، لا تتحرّكوا‬
They'll go back into the sea eventually.
‫ستعود إلى البحر تدريجيًا على الأرجح‬
When they do, we paddle as hard as possible.
‫ومن ثم سنجدف بكل قوتنا‬
Are you serious?!
‫هل أنت جاد؟!‬
Shut it, idiot!
‫أحمق!‬
Sorry...
‫المعذرة...‬
Hold on a sec...!
‫تمهّل...‬
If it does that...
‫إن فعلها...‬
He's gonna sneeze!
‫فسيعطس!‬
– What?!
‫ماذا؟!‬
Wow! It feels like we're flying!
‫مذهل! وكأنّنا نطير!‬
We are flying!
‫إنّنا نطير فعلًا!‬
Looks like we're back on course...
‫يبدو أنّنا عُدنا إلى مسارنا الصحيح‬
We should be seeing the Red Line any moment now.
‫سنرى الريد لاين في أيّ لحظة‬
Are we finally going into the Grand Line?!
‫سنصل إلى الغراند لاين أخيرًا!‬
Hey, Sanji! We're here, we're here, we're finally here!
‫يا سانجي! سنصل أخيرًا! أخيرًا، أخيرًا!‬
That hurts!
‫هذا مؤلم!‬
Sorry...
‫أعتذر‬
Zoro!
‫زورو!‬
We're here, we're here! But...
‫سنصل، سنصل!‬ ‫لكن...‬
We're here, we're here, we're here! is the drawing an accurate representation of what we'll find?
‫سنصل، سنصل، سنصل!‬ ‫أتمثّل الرسمة ما سنراه فعلًا؟‬
Quit it!
‫كفى!‬
Look at this!
‫انظروا لهذه!‬
I'd heard the rumors about it, and it's drawn on this map, too!
‫سمعتُ إشاعاتٍ عديدة، وقد رُسم في هذه الخريطة كذلك‬
If all of that is true, then the entrance to the Grand Line is a mountain!
‫فإن صحّت الإشاعات، فمدخل الغراند لاين جبل!‬
A mountain?
‫جبل؟‬
We gotta crash into it?
‫سنصطدم بجبل؟!‬
You're kidding, right?
‫لا يُعقَل‬
I doubted it myself, but the map shows canals leading to the mountain.
‫راودني الشكّ، لكن الخريطة تُظهر قنواتٍ تؤدّي إلى جبل‬
That might mean we have to go up it!
‫ولعلّ علينا صعوده!‬
Cool!
‫مثير!‬
What are you talking about?!
‫ماذا تقول؟!‬
Even with canals or whatever, a ship can't climb up a mountain!
‫مهما كانت تلك القنوات فالسفينة محالٌ عليها صعود الجبال!‬
But that's what the map says!
‫هذا ما تُظهره الخريطة!‬
Exactly! Nami would never say anything wrong!
‫أجل، نامي-سان لا تنطق إلا صوابًا!‬
You stole that map from Buggy, right?
‫سرقتِ هذه الخريطة من باغي، صحيح؟‬
Can we really trust it?
‫أيمكننا الوثوق بها؟‬
H-Hey!
‫أ-أنتم!‬
Someone help me move the whipstaff!
‫فليساعدني أحدٌ في الدفة!‬
Sanji! Give Usopp a hand!
‫ساعد أوسوب يا سانجي-كن‬
It won't budge!
‫إنّه لا يتحرك!‬
I can't think with all his shouting!
‫ضجّته تمنعني من التفكير‬
It won't move! Someone help!
‫إنّه لا يتحرك، فليساعدني أحد!‬
Right away, Nami!
‫حاضر يا نامي-سان!‬
Here I go!
‫هيّا‬
D-Doesn't this current seem a bit strong?!
‫أ-ألا يبدو هذا التيّار قويًّا؟!‬
Usopp, say that again!
‫ماذا قلت توًّا يا أوسوب؟‬
"D-Doesn't this current seem a bit strong?!"
‫أ-ألا يبدو هذا التيار قويًّا؟!‬
Current...
‫تيّار...‬
That's it!
‫فهمت!‬
What's it?
‫ماذا؟‬
The canals do go up the mountain!
‫علينا صعود الجبال حقًّا!‬
You're still on that?
‫أما زلتِ تصرينَ على ذلك؟‬
Look here!
‫انظروا هنا!‬
See?
‫اصغوا بتمعّن،‬
The guiding light was definitely pointing to here.
‫هنا كان يشير الضوء المُرشد‬
Right on the Red Line: Reverse Mountain!
‫الجبل المعكوس الموجود في الريد لاين!‬
Hey! What do I do now?!
‫أنتم! ماذا أفعل بهذه؟‬
See these canals here?
‫توجد قنوات هنا، أليس كذلك؟‬
If major currents from the four seas all flowed toward this mountain...
‫إن كانت كلّ التيارات الكبرى من البحار الأربعة تتدفق نحو هذا الجبل،‬
Then the four currents would go up these canals, collide at the top,
‫فإنّ هذه التيارات الأربعة ستصعد إلى أعلى هذه القنوات وتصطدم عاليًا‬
and flow into the Grand Line!
‫ومن ثم تتدفّق إلى الغراند لاين!‬
Reverse Mountain is a winter island,
‫بما أن الجبل المعكوس جزيرة شتائيّة،‬
so any currents that collide with the Red Line will go into the depths.
‫لذا فإنَّ أيّ تيارٍ يرتطم بالريد لاين سينحدر إلى الأعماق‬
If we screw up and miss the entrance to the canal...
‫إن أخطأنا وضيّعنا مدخل القناة،‬
the Going Merry will crash into the Red Line...
‫فإنّ غوينغ ميري ستصطدم مباشرةً بالريد لاين...‬
and get completely wrecked!
‫وتتحطّم!‬
Then we'd end up at the bottom of the ocean. Get it?
‫وسنكون حينها في قاع البحر. أفهمتم؟‬
Oh, very interesting!
‫هكذا إذًا!‬
So, basically, it's a mystery mountain!
‫باختصار، إنّه جبلٌ غامض!‬
Well, I guess you wouldn't...
‫توقعت ألّا تفهم...‬
All in all, now that we're on this current,
‫على أيّ حال، ما دُمنا فوق هذا التيار،‬
as long as we steer correctly,
‫وما دمنا لم نُخطئ في توجيه الدفة‬
it's a straight shot to the summit of Reverse Mountain!
‫فسنتمكّن من الوصول إلى قمة الجبل المعكوس مباشرةً!‬
You're amazing, Nami!
‫إنّكِ مذهلة يا نامي-سان!‬
I've never heard of someone going up a mountain by boat.
‫لم أسمع بسفنٍ تصعدُ جبالًا من قبل‬
I've heard some stories!
‫أمّا أنا فقد سمعت البعض‬
About the mystery mountain?
‫قصصًا عن الجبل الغامض؟‬
No.
‫كلّا‬
I heard that half of everyone who heads to the Grand Line die before entering...
‫سمعتُ أنّ نصف من يتوجّهون إلى الغراند لاين يلقون حتفهم قبل بلوغه‬
I knew getting in wouldn't be easy.
‫كنتُ أعلم أنّ دخوله لن يكون سهلًا‬
Sanji! Could you get the sail?
‫تولَّ أمر الشراع يا سانجي-كن‬
Of course, Nami!
‫حاضر يا نامي-سان!‬
Luffy! Help out!
‫ساعدني يا لوفي‬
Hey!
‫يا رفاق!‬
I see the mystery mountain!
‫أرى الجبل الغامض!‬
– Wh-What?! – What?!
‫ماذا؟‬
Th-That's insanely huge!
‫إ-إنّه ضخمٌ جدًّا!‬
So that's the Red Line, huh?!
‫أهذا هو الريد لاين؟‬
Th-Th-The t-top's all the way above the clouds!
‫لـ-لـ-لا أرى القمّة بسبب الغيوم!‬
We're getting sucked in!
‫سيسحبنا!‬
Hold the rudder tight!
‫أمسكوا الدفة جيّدًا‬
– On it!
‫اعتمد علينا‬
N-Nami! Wh-Where's the entrance?!
‫نـ-نامي! أين المدخل؟!‬
We're gonna crash if we keep going this way!
‫سنصطدم بالصخور إن واصلنا بهذا الاتجاه!‬
The crack in that cliff...
‫الصدع في ذلك الجرف...‬
Nami! What do we do?!
‫نامي! ماذا نفعل؟!‬
Keep going straight ahead!
‫استمرّا في التقدّم!‬
Are you sure?!
‫هل أنتِ جادّة؟!‬
Just do it!
‫لا عليكم‬
Nami! Is that the entrance?
‫أذاك المدخل يا نامي؟‬
Most likely!
‫على الأرجح‬
I can't believe this...!
‫لا أصدّق هذا!‬
The damn ocean really is flowing up the mountain!
‫يتدفّق البحر إلى أعلى الجبل فعلًا!‬
We gotta be careful sailing through those gates!
‫علينا أن نعبر هذه البوابات بسلاسة،‬
If we don't get it just right, the ship is done for!
‫وإلّا ستتحطّم السفينة إلى أشلاء!‬
W-We're a little off! More to the right! The right!
‫إ-إننا ننحرف عن مسارنا! إلى اليمين أكثر! اليمين، اليمين!‬
The right?! Go starboard!
‫اليمين؟! إلى الميمنة!‬
C-Come on, now!
‫تمهلّوا‬
– The whipstaff!
‫الدفة!‬
Gum-Gum Balloon!
‫فاكهة المطّاط‬ ‫غومو غومو نو‬
Luffy!
‫لوفي!‬
Grab on!
‫أمسك بي‬
– We made it!
‫نجحنا!‬
Now it's just a straight shot to the summit!
‫والآن، إلى القمّة مباشرةً!‬
A-Awesome!
‫مـ-مذهل!‬
Awesome, right?
‫مذهل، أليس كذلك؟‬
We're in the clouds!
‫إنّنا داخل الغيوم!‬
So cool!
‫مذهل!‬
Now we're above the clouds!
‫إنّنا فوق الغيوم الآن!‬
Look! It's the summit! The summit!
‫انظروا! القمّة، إنّها القمّة!‬
Yahoo!
‫مرحى!‬
I see it!
‫رأيتُه...‬
This is the greatest sea in the world!
‫أعظم بحار العالم...‬
The Grand Line!
‫الغراند لاين!‬
The One Piece is somewhere up ahead!
‫الون بيس موجودٌ في مكانٍ ما أمامنا!‬
Go!
‫انطلاق!‬
Did you hear that just now?
‫أسمعتم شيئًا توًّا؟‬
Wasn't it just the wind?
‫أليست رياحًا فحسب؟‬
It must be from all the weird landforms around here.
‫لا بد من وجود تضاريس غير عادية‬
What's that?
‫ما هذا؟‬
Nami! I see a mountain up ahead!
‫نامي-سان! أرى جبلًا أمامنا!‬
A mountain?! That can't be right!
‫جبل؟! هذا مستحيل!‬
But there's really one there!
‫لكنّه أمامنا فعلًا!‬
Who cares?! Go!
‫من يهتم؟! لننطلق!‬
It should be open sea once we pass the Twin Capes up ahead!
‫بعدَ تجاوزِنا الرَّأسين التوأم لا ينبغي أن يعترضنا شيء‬
Oh, crap!
‫مصيبة!‬
It's not a mountain!
‫لم يكن جبلًا!‬
It's a big black wall!
‫مجرّد جدار أسود‬
No, it's not! That's...
‫لا، ليس كذلك‬
What is it then?!
‫ماذا يكون إذًا؟‬
I-I-I-It's...
‫إ-إ-إنه...‬
It's a whale!
‫إنه حوت!‬
Wh-Wh-What are we g-gonna do?!
‫ما-ما-ماذا سنفعل؟!‬
We should fight it!
‫أعلينا مواجهته؟‬
Are you crazy?! How are we gonna fight that?!
‫كفاك مزاحًا! كيف لنا أن نواجهه؟!‬
B-B-But, i-i-it's blocking our way!
‫لـ-لـ-لكنّه يعترض طريقنا!‬
What are we gonna do?!
‫ماذا سنفعل؟‬
Hold on a sec!
‫تمهّلوا لحظة!‬
If it looks like a wall from this close, where are its eyes?!
‫إن بدا كجدار من هذه المسافة... فأين عيناه؟‬
That's right! Maybe it hasn't noticed us yet!
‫صحيح، لعلّه لم يلحظنا بعد‬
Either way, we're about to crash into it!
‫نحن قاب قوسين من الارتطام به!‬
Hey! There's an opening on the left!
‫مهلًا! بإمكاننا العبور يسارًا‬
Port! Hard to port!
‫الميسرة! إلى الميسرة!‬
But the whipstaff is broken!
‫لكن الدفة مكسورة‬
Well, figure something out! I'll help!
‫تَصَرَّف!‬
Oh, yeah!
‫لحظة‬
I've got an idea!
‫راودتني فكرة‬
Luffy...?
‫لوفي؟‬
Hey, what are you doing?!
‫مهلًا، ما الذي تنوي فعله؟‬
This isn't working!
‫لا فائدة!‬
The ship won't turn!
‫السفينة لا تستدير!‬
Dammit!
‫تبًّا!‬
Don't give up!
‫لا تستسلموا!‬
Is this it...?!
‫أحانت نهايتنا؟!‬
The cannon?!
‫مدفع؟!‬
Alright! Did it stop?
‫جيد، هل توقفنا؟‬
We're screwed...
‫هذا الأسوأ...‬
Yeah, this is it...
‫سنهلك...‬
My special seat!
‫مقعدي المفضل!‬
Let's...
‫لـ...‬
Let's book it while we still can!
‫لنهرب من هنا قبل فوات الأوان!‬
What the heck is going on?!
‫ما الذي يحدث هنا؟!‬
Is it so big that it didn't even feel it?!
‫أمِن ضخامته لم يلاحظ؟‬
Or is it just slow?!
‫أم لعلّه بطيء؟‬
Who cares?! Let's get the hell out of here!
‫من يدري؟ لنهرب بسرعة!‬
My ears!
‫أذناي تؤلمانني!‬
Paddle! Just keep paddling!
‫جدف، جدف فحسب‬
We have to get away from it!
‫علينا الابتعاد عنه‬
Luffy...?
‫لوفي؟‬
You!
‫أنت!‬
What the hell did you do to my special seat?!
‫ما الذي فعلته بمقعدي المفضل؟!‬
– You dumbass!
‫مغفل!‬
How was that, huh?! Bring it on, you bastard!
‫ما رأيك بها؟ أرِني ما لديك أيها الوغد‬
– Shut up already, you idiot!
‫اصمت أيها الأحمق!‬
Wh-What?
‫مـ-ماذا؟‬
Luffy!
‫لوفي!‬
I'm not gonna die!
‫لن أموت!‬
What am I gonna do?
‫ماذا أفعل؟‬
They all got eaten...
‫التهمهم جميعًا!‬
Hey, you! Spit them out! Give everyone back!
‫أنت! ابصقهم وأعدهم لي!‬
Spit them out already! Listen to me!
‫ابصقهم، ألم أقل لك أن تُعدهم؟!‬
You–
‫أيّها الـ...‬
You... You jerk!
‫أيّها... أيّها الوغد!‬
Are you diving?! Stop it!
‫أستغوص؟! توقف!‬
Hey! I said stop! Hey!
‫اسمعني! قلتُ لك توقف! انتظر!‬
Please, stop! Give my friends back!
‫انتظر رجاءً! أعد لي رفاقي!‬
Hey!
‫أنت!‬
Stop it already!
‫قلتُ لك توقف!‬
We were just about to go on an adventure!
‫كنّا سنخوض مغامرات عديدة معًا،‬
I can't lose them!
‫إنهم أعزاء على قلبي!‬
Give them back!
‫أعدهم!‬
So, what do you think?
‫ماذا... تظنون؟‬
What do I think...?
‫ماذا أظن؟‬
What should I think?
‫فيم عسايَ أن أُفكر؟‬
H-H-H-H-How...?
‫كـ-كـ-كـ-كيف...‬
We were definitely swallowed by that whale...
‫إنني واثقٌ بأنّ الحوت ابتلعنا‬
Is this a dream?
‫أهذا حلم؟‬
Yeah, it's gotta be a dream.
‫نعم، على الأرجح أنه حلم‬
Then, how do you explain that island and house?
‫فكيف تُفسِّر تلك الجزيرة وذلك البيت؟‬
Hallucinations.
‫لا بد أننا نُهلوس‬
So, that's also...?
‫وهذا أيضًا؟!‬
– It's an imperial squid!
‫حبّار ملكيّ عملاق!‬
Looks like someone lives there.
‫يبدو أن أحدًا يسكن هناك‬
Let's hope they're human.
‫عسى أن يكون بشريًا‬
I've had enough. I wanna go home.
‫اكتفيت، أريد العودة للمنزل‬
Luffy's gone, too... What's gonna happen to us?
‫حتى لوفي اختفى، ماذا سيحلّ بنا؟‬
You're right! Where's Luffy?!
‫على ذكرك هذا، أين لوفي؟‬
What the heck is all this?
‫ما هذا؟‬
Why is there a door to a hallway inside a whale?
‫لماذا هنالك باب وممّر داخل حوتٍ؟‬
A ship...
‫سفينة...‬
Sh-Sh-Should we f-fire the cannon at that island?!
‫هـ-هـ-هـ-هل نطلق على تلك الجزيرة؟‬
No, hold on a sec...
‫لا، انتظر لحظة...‬
Someone's coming out...
‫خرج أحدٌ...‬